<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CS 493</title>
    <link>http://classes.engr.oregonstate.edu/eecs/perpetual/cs493-400/</link>
    <description>Recent content on CS 493</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="http://classes.engr.oregonstate.edu/eecs/perpetual/cs493-400/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Overview</title>
      <link>http://classes.engr.oregonstate.edu/eecs/perpetual/cs493-400/modules/1-course-rest-cloud-overview/1-course-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://classes.engr.oregonstate.edu/eecs/perpetual/cs493-400/modules/1-course-rest-cloud-overview/1-course-overview/</guid>
      <description>Course Overview Introduction This course focuses on cloud API development. Those represent the two major components of the class: cloud based computing and API development. Cloud computing is basically computing that is done on distributed computers all over the world. Web API development involved creating applications that internet connected devices can interact with to accomplish certain tasks. The combination will mean that we are creating applications on cloud based computers which we can interact with over the internet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deciding on URLs</title>
      <link>http://classes.engr.oregonstate.edu/eecs/perpetual/cs493-400/modules/3-rest-api-creation/1-url-selection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://classes.engr.oregonstate.edu/eecs/perpetual/cs493-400/modules/3-rest-api-creation/1-url-selection/</guid>
      <description>Deciding on URLs Introduction In this section we return to the concept of resources representing URLs. We are going to talk in some more detail about what this means and how it is applied to a web application. Everything in this section will assume the data is stored as a simple JSON representation. For our example we are going to to use a lodging provider that has provides lodgings to guests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to REST</title>
      <link>http://classes.engr.oregonstate.edu/eecs/perpetual/cs493-400/modules/2-rest-api-use/1-rest-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://classes.engr.oregonstate.edu/eecs/perpetual/cs493-400/modules/2-rest-api-use/1-rest-intro/</guid>
      <description>Introduction to REST Introduction Representational State Transfer, much more commonly called REST is a very specific way of designing an API. The core concept of a REST Web API is that all the URLs identify resources, we will talk about this in some depth. Another important aspect of REST Web APIs is that they are stateless. The server does not store any information about the current state of a client.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RESTful Links</title>
      <link>http://classes.engr.oregonstate.edu/eecs/perpetual/cs493-400/modules/5-advanced-rest-api/1-internal-links/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://classes.engr.oregonstate.edu/eecs/perpetual/cs493-400/modules/5-advanced-rest-api/1-internal-links/</guid>
      <description> RESTful Links Introduction TOPIC 1 HERE! SUBTOPIC HERE!  where video_identifier is replaced with the id of the video found in the kaltura video URL -- Activity Review </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RESTful Relationships</title>
      <link>http://classes.engr.oregonstate.edu/eecs/perpetual/cs493-400/modules/4-more-rest-api-creation/1-relationships/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://classes.engr.oregonstate.edu/eecs/perpetual/cs493-400/modules/4-more-rest-api-creation/1-relationships/</guid>
      <description> RESTful Relationships Introduction TOPIC 1 HERE! SUBTOPIC HERE!  where video_identifier is replaced with the id of the video found in the kaltura video URL -- Activity Review </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Computing Overview</title>
      <link>http://classes.engr.oregonstate.edu/eecs/perpetual/cs493-400/modules/1-course-rest-cloud-overview/2-cloud-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://classes.engr.oregonstate.edu/eecs/perpetual/cs493-400/modules/1-course-rest-cloud-overview/2-cloud-overview/</guid>
      <description>Cloud Computing Overview Introduction In my personal experience there are not a whole lot of people who like the term &amp;ldquo;The Cloud&amp;rdquo; in the programming world. It is a great marketing tool, but it is often found in sentences which are also home to &amp;ldquo;incubating disruptive synergies&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;impactful value-added transformational e-future proofing&amp;rdquo;. It is fairly inspecific corporate jargon at this point. So lets clarify what thing(s) we might actually be talking about when we use the term &amp;ldquo;the cloud&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTTP Verbs</title>
      <link>http://classes.engr.oregonstate.edu/eecs/perpetual/cs493-400/modules/2-rest-api-use/2-http-verbs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://classes.engr.oregonstate.edu/eecs/perpetual/cs493-400/modules/2-rest-api-use/2-http-verbs/</guid>
      <description>HTTP Verbs Introduction Verbs are the key to letting us interact with REST APIs. Before we had mentioned that https://example.com/class/1/student/5 might refer to a student with an ID of 5 enrolled in a class with an id of 1. Broadly speaking there are 4 major things we could do at this point. We could create a new thing and add it to the student, maybe an assignment for example. We could read the data about the student or the class in the database.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Objects in Good API Design</title>
      <link>http://classes.engr.oregonstate.edu/eecs/perpetual/cs493-400/modules/3-rest-api-creation/2-oo-practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://classes.engr.oregonstate.edu/eecs/perpetual/cs493-400/modules/3-rest-api-creation/2-oo-practices/</guid>
      <description>Objects in Good API Design Introduction REST APIs lend themselves well to object oriented design. We are mainly using JavaScript in this class with Node.js, so it may not be quite as clean as it would be in something like C#, but the same principles will sill apply, so lets take a look!
What are the main Types? From the last section, we know there are broadly two sorts of things we will be dealing with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pagination in REST</title>
      <link>http://classes.engr.oregonstate.edu/eecs/perpetual/cs493-400/modules/5-advanced-rest-api/2-pagination/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://classes.engr.oregonstate.edu/eecs/perpetual/cs493-400/modules/5-advanced-rest-api/2-pagination/</guid>
      <description> Pagination in REST Introduction TOPIC 1 HERE! SUBTOPIC HERE!  where video_identifier is replaced with the id of the video found in the kaltura video URL -- Activity Review </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>REST Case Study One</title>
      <link>http://classes.engr.oregonstate.edu/eecs/perpetual/cs493-400/modules/4-more-rest-api-creation/2-case-study-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://classes.engr.oregonstate.edu/eecs/perpetual/cs493-400/modules/4-more-rest-api-creation/2-case-study-one/</guid>
      <description> REST Case Study One Introduction TOPIC 1 HERE! SUBTOPIC HERE!  where video_identifier is replaced with the id of the video found in the kaltura video URL -- Activity Review </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>API Introduction</title>
      <link>http://classes.engr.oregonstate.edu/eecs/perpetual/cs493-400/modules/1-course-rest-cloud-overview/3-api-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://classes.engr.oregonstate.edu/eecs/perpetual/cs493-400/modules/1-course-rest-cloud-overview/3-api-overview/</guid>
      <description>API Introduction Introduction An Application Programming Interface or API is the mechanism by which a programmer might interface with an application. APIs exists at almost all levels of the software stack. Operating systems expose systems calls as an API that allows access to the lower levels of the operating system. C++ libraries expose APIs that allow you to access various data structures or features in the language. The standard template library is a good example of this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Common Data Formats</title>
      <link>http://classes.engr.oregonstate.edu/eecs/perpetual/cs493-400/modules/2-rest-api-use/3-data-formats/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://classes.engr.oregonstate.edu/eecs/perpetual/cs493-400/modules/2-rest-api-use/3-data-formats/</guid>
      <description>Common Data Formats Introduction When working with APIs you might encounter several formats of data. Most commonly you will see JSON, XML and potentially some sort of format made for humans, like HTML or plain text. In this class the only data format you will need to work with is JSON so this will primarily serve as a quick refresher on JSON format.
JavaScript Object Notation This notation is more or less the same notation used to describe JavaScript Objects but it is somewhat more strict.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>REST Case Study Two</title>
      <link>http://classes.engr.oregonstate.edu/eecs/perpetual/cs493-400/modules/4-more-rest-api-creation/3-case-study-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://classes.engr.oregonstate.edu/eecs/perpetual/cs493-400/modules/4-more-rest-api-creation/3-case-study-two/</guid>
      <description> REST Case Study Two Introduction TOPIC 1 HERE! SUBTOPIC HERE!  where video_identifier is replaced with the id of the video found in the kaltura video URL -- Activity Review </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demo of REST API Use</title>
      <link>http://classes.engr.oregonstate.edu/eecs/perpetual/cs493-400/modules/2-rest-api-use/4-use-demo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://classes.engr.oregonstate.edu/eecs/perpetual/cs493-400/modules/2-rest-api-use/4-use-demo/</guid>
      <description>Demo of REST API Use Introduction We are going to walk through using a real live API to see what it practically looks like to do these sorts of tasks. This video uses the Box API reference as a guide when it comes to setting up the calls. This API is well documented and shows examples for every call. The Postman API tool is used to interact with the API via a somewhat graphical interface.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google App Engine and Node.js</title>
      <link>http://classes.engr.oregonstate.edu/eecs/perpetual/cs493-400/modules/3-rest-api-creation/3-gae-node-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://classes.engr.oregonstate.edu/eecs/perpetual/cs493-400/modules/3-rest-api-creation/3-gae-node-basics/</guid>
      <description>Google App Engine and Node.js Introduction It can be difficult getting a new tool or library up or running. I would encourage you to try this weeks assignment without going through this section. Once you depart school and are working professionally you likely will be tasked with sometimes setting up new projects from scratch. This is often a challenging task as knowing where to start can be hard to figure out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tools and Software Setup</title>
      <link>http://classes.engr.oregonstate.edu/eecs/perpetual/cs493-400/modules/1-course-rest-cloud-overview/4-tools-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://classes.engr.oregonstate.edu/eecs/perpetual/cs493-400/modules/1-course-rest-cloud-overview/4-tools-setup/</guid>
      <description>Tools and Software Setup Introduction There are a few tools and providers we will need to work with throughout this class. In this section we are going to get them set up and working so we know, down the road, that we don&amp;rsquo;t need to worry about getting any of this configured and we can focus on the topics at hand.
Postman Setting this one up is pretty straight forward.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>