<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Course introduction, cloud introduction and REST introduction on CS 493</title>
    <link>http://classes.engr.oregonstate.edu/eecs/perpetual/cs493-400/modules/1-course-rest-cloud-overview/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Course introduction, cloud introduction and REST introduction on CS 493</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="http://classes.engr.oregonstate.edu/eecs/perpetual/cs493-400/modules/1-course-rest-cloud-overview/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Course Overview</title>
      <link>http://classes.engr.oregonstate.edu/eecs/perpetual/cs493-400/modules/1-course-rest-cloud-overview/1-course-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://classes.engr.oregonstate.edu/eecs/perpetual/cs493-400/modules/1-course-rest-cloud-overview/1-course-overview/</guid>
      <description>Course Overview Introduction This course focuses on cloud API development. Those represent the two major components of the class: cloud based computing and API development. Cloud computing is basically computing that is done on distributed computers all over the world. Web API development involved creating applications that internet connected devices can interact with to accomplish certain tasks. The combination will mean that we are creating applications on cloud based computers which we can interact with over the internet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Computing Overview</title>
      <link>http://classes.engr.oregonstate.edu/eecs/perpetual/cs493-400/modules/1-course-rest-cloud-overview/2-cloud-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://classes.engr.oregonstate.edu/eecs/perpetual/cs493-400/modules/1-course-rest-cloud-overview/2-cloud-overview/</guid>
      <description>Cloud Computing Overview Introduction In my personal experience there are not a whole lot of people who like the term &amp;ldquo;The Cloud&amp;rdquo; in the programming world. It is a great marketing tool, but it is often found in sentences which are also home to &amp;ldquo;incubating disruptive synergies&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;impactful value-added transformational e-future proofing&amp;rdquo;. It is fairly inspecific corporate jargon at this point. So lets clarify what thing(s) we might actually be talking about when we use the term &amp;ldquo;the cloud&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>API Introduction</title>
      <link>http://classes.engr.oregonstate.edu/eecs/perpetual/cs493-400/modules/1-course-rest-cloud-overview/3-api-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://classes.engr.oregonstate.edu/eecs/perpetual/cs493-400/modules/1-course-rest-cloud-overview/3-api-overview/</guid>
      <description>API Introduction Introduction An Application Programming Interface or API is the mechanism by which a programmer might interface with an application. APIs exists at almost all levels of the software stack. Operating systems expose systems calls as an API that allows access to the lower levels of the operating system. C++ libraries expose APIs that allow you to access various data structures or features in the language. The standard template library is a good example of this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tools and Software Setup</title>
      <link>http://classes.engr.oregonstate.edu/eecs/perpetual/cs493-400/modules/1-course-rest-cloud-overview/4-tools-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://classes.engr.oregonstate.edu/eecs/perpetual/cs493-400/modules/1-course-rest-cloud-overview/4-tools-setup/</guid>
      <description>Tools and Software Setup Introduction There are a few tools and providers we will need to work with throughout this class. In this section we are going to get them set up and working so we know, down the road, that we don&amp;rsquo;t need to worry about getting any of this configured and we can focus on the topics at hand.
Postman Setting this one up is pretty straight forward.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>